# **Shaker Kattoula**

Oceanside, CA | smkattoula@gmail.com | Linkedin.com/in/shakerkattoula | Portfolio: shakerkattoula.com

#### Summary

Software Developer from San Diego with a strong passion for problem-solving and engineering creative solutions using code. Reflective communicator and collaborative team member. Backed with over 5+ years of professional customer service and operations management

#### **Technical Skills**

HTML, CSS/SCSS, JavaScript, React, NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, jQuery, Bootstrap, Git Flow/GitHub, TDD(jest/enzyme), REST API's(JSON), CRUD functionality, State Management (Redux, Context API), User Authentication(JWT), Responsive Design, MVC design pattern

## **Projects**

September 2020

## **Budget Tracker**

Github: github.com/smkattoula/MERN-Budget-Tracker | Live Demo: dry-wave-28460.herokuapp.com/ A full-stack application utilizing the MERN framework. This application allows the user to track their income and expenses. Implements REST API's with axios, CRUD functionality, JSON, User Authentication using JWT and bcryptJS, MongoDB with mongoose, State Management using Context API, Styling of the UI with CSS, use of React libraries such as BrowserRouter, React-Router-Dom, Hooks, Bootstrap/Reactstrap and more.

August 2020

### **Ticket Tracker**

Github: github.com/smkattoula/MERN-Ticket-Tracker | Live Demo: safe-thicket-31589.herokuapp.com/ A full-stack application utilizing the MERN framework. This application allows users to create tickets to track their bugs, issues, or tasks to complete. Implements REST API's with axios, CRUD functionality, JSON, User Authentication using JWT and bcryptJS, MongoDB with mongoose, State Management using Context API, Styling of the UI with CSS, use of React libraries such as BrowserRouter, React-Router-Dom, Hooks, Bootstrap/Reactstrap and more.

#### **Professional Experience**

April 2020 - June 2020

## Full Stack Software Developer Intern (Remote), Victorise, Carlsbad, CA

- Used the MERN stack to connect front-end/backend and improve existing web application UI features
- Created UX analysis bug reports for both web and mobile applications Improved functionality of UI features on mobile application using React Native
- Communicated effectively with the project manager on a daily basis to ensure timely completion of tasks and quality assurance
- Utilized weekly sprint planning via Agile methodology

January 2020 - April 2020

# Full Stack Web Developer, LEARN Academy, San Diego, CA

- Completed over 480 hours of hands-on coding experience in settings that include pair-programming, mob projects, and individual work as part of an intensive, 4-month coding boot camp in San Diego
- Created full-stack applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, and PostgreSQL
- Active participant in pair programming and demonstrated effective communication/collaborative skills
- Volunteered as a Teacher's Assistant to aid new students in learning the fundamentals of code

#### **Education**

August 2015 - May 2019

California State University of San Marcos - Bachelor's Degree, Psychology